<resources>
    <string name="app_name">YogaApp</string>
    <string name="yoga_practice">Yoga Practice</string>
    <string name="detailed_exercises">Detailed\nexercises</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="questions_about_yoga">Questions about yoga</string>
    <string name="what_is_asana_translation_and_interpretation">What is asana: translation and interpretation\n</string>
    <string name="title_second">Asana means \"stable body posture\" in Sanskrit. Such postures activate various systems of the body and saturate every cell with energy.\nIt is important not only to stay in a particular position, but also to breathe correctly. Then our heart, like a good motor, works more actively and our organs receive enough oxygen. Controlled breathing is what distinguishes yoga from gymnastics. By noticing each inhalation and exhalation, the practitioner can easily keep the focus on their sensations and maintain asana. At the same time yoga is not exhausting and does not make you literally drop dead after training.\nEveryone can \"adjust\" the practice to himself, even if the last time he did physical \neducation at school.\nTraining does not require\nextreme skills and pumped-up muscles,  but if you get on the mat regularly, there will be changes noticeable to the naked eye\n</string>
    <string name="practice_1_1">How many asanas are there in yoga?</string>
    <string name="practice_1_2"><![CDATA[There is a famous statement of Goraksha: \"There are as many asanas as there are species of different living beings. Shiva spoke of 8,400,000 asanas and he alone knew them. Out of this number, he selected 84 of which 4 are the most important and useful. These four - siddha, padma, simha and bhadra asanas are the best\"\nAsana consists of three stages: entering the pose, holding and exiting. It is important to stay in the asana for some time - from one minute. But the effect of practice will also be during dynamic work. For beginners at the first stages it is better to watch not the number and intensity of poses, but the correctness of their fulfilment. \nEach asana is a rejection of purely human nature and a repetition of the original divine movement, so it is important to hold the poses as accurately as possible. And if you have never practised before, for the first time it is better to go to a studio for group or individual lessons. The teacher will be able to create a unique set of asanas for you and will be able to tell you if you are doing something wrong\nAsanas help to keep everything in normal tonus - muscles, joints and organs. The postures have different effects:\n\n]]></string>
    <string name="practice_2_1">Yoga exercises: what benefits they bring to the body</string>
    <string name="practice_2_2">Standing asanas help to correct posture, find balance and develop joint and muscle elasticity. Standing yoga is a great foundation for more advanced practices in the future.\nSitting asanas can help you get rid of pain in your knees, ankles, hips or spine. Sitting yoga postures set you up for total relaxation and dialogue with yourself.\nInverted asanas allow you to forget about stress and disconnect from the problems of the outside world. These poses nourish the body with energy, give emotional balance and restore blood supply to the brain.\nInclines stretch the spine and the back of the hips, give a charge of vigour, relieve the feeling of heaviness in the back.\nBends help to eliminate slouching and tone the whole front part of the body - chest, abs, hips. They also improve digestion and open the chest, which improves oxygen circulation.\nTwists literally revitalise the spine, as they nourish the intervertebral discs. Such poses perfectly stimulate the work of internal organs.\nAsanas lying down help to restore the body after a hard day or illness. They are useful for women suffering from menstrual cramps, for asthmatics and people with digestive problems.\n\n</string>
    <string name="practice_3_1">How many seconds to hold a yoga pose?</string>
    <string name="practice_3_2">Asanas are stable positions, which means it is better to remain still and calm for some time, usually from 30 seconds to 5 minutes. It all depends on the level of training and the complexity of the asana itself, for example, in Shavasana you can stay up to 15 minutes. It is important not to forget about breathing, it helps to hold asanas. At first it may be difficult to keep the pose, to concentrate on sensations and to watch your breathing. But gradually the body will get used to the strain\n\n</string>
    <string name="practice_4_1">How does yoga end?</string>
    <string name="practice_4_2">Usually the complex ends with total relaxation - Shavasana, when students calm their breathing and let go of all worries. It is important not to cling to the flaring thoughts, but to let them flow quietly from one to another without getting stuck. Relaxing asanas are very important because they teach you to listen to your sensations and desires. Shavasana perfectly consolidates the result of practice, helps the body to internalise the experience, and the mind to switch from physical activity to complete relaxation.\n\n</string>
    <string name="practice_5_1">What is static in yoga?</string>
    <string name="practice_5_2">Static is based on holding an asana for a long time. Whereas vinyasa flow requires dynamic movement from one pose to another, here practitioners try to hold their postures for a long time. Static teaches us to hear and listen to our body at a deep level: by staying in a pose, we study it from the inside, find new vectors of work, understand the form literally centimetre by centimetre. And at the same time we strengthen muscles. Practically any asana can be performed in static mode - from Tadasana to Shirshasana. Virabhadrasana I and II, Uttthita Trikonasana, Vrikshasana are excellent starting yoga poses where you can learn to breathe deeply and explore the possibilities of the body in static mode.</string>
    <string name="asana_instructions">Asana Instructions</string>
    <string name="asana_1">Tadasana -\nmountain pose</string>
    <string name="asana_1_title">Stand up straight, feet together - thumbs and heels touch each other.\nTense the quadriceps and pull up the kneecaps.\nPoint the pubic bone towards yourself, and pull the abdomen and lower ribs inwards.\nTurn the shoulders back slightly and lower them down - following the shoulder blades they seem to \"flow\" to the floor.\nHands hang freely along the body, fingers pointing downwards.\nFeel the support under the feet and stretch into one even strong string - from the heels to the top of the head.\n</string>
    <string name="asana_1_in">stand still for about a minute, breathe evenly and deeply, launch a wave of relaxation on each exhalation.</string>
    <string name="asana_1_exit">Exit: slowly move to the next asana.</string>
    <string name="asana_2">Vrikshasana\ntree pose</string>
    <string name="asana_2_title">In Tadasana, lift the right leg bent at the knee. Place the foot as close to the groin as possible. If this is not possible, lower it lower - on the shin. It is inadmissible from the point of view of injury safety to rest on the knee.\nRaise your hands up or join your palms in namaste in front of your chest. In the second case, press the bases of the palms tightly together, with the thumbs pointing towards the sternum and the other fingers pointing away from the body.\nPull the knee of the supporting leg upwards by activating the quadriceps.\nSmooth the lumbar flexion: tuck the tailbone inwards, tighten the navel and lower ribs.\nShoulders downwards, neck free, head pulling the spine upwards.\nStay at -8 cycles of breathing.\nReturn to Tadasana and perform on the other side.\nIf it is difficult to keep your balance, you can lean against a wall or chair or place your hands on your waist. It is also recommended to look at a fixed point in front of you - this also helps to keep your balance\n</string>
    <string name="asana_3">Uttthita Trikonasana stretched triangle pose</string>
    <string name="asana_3_title">From Tadasana take a step to the right, spreading your legs about a metre wide (the distance is calculated individually and depends on the proportions of the person).\nStraight arms are parallel to the mat.\nTighten the kneecaps slightly, the joints should be relaxed.\nTurn the right foot along the mat forwards, the left foot inwards at an angle of about 45 degrees.\nBring the body behind the right hand and place the palm of the hand on the shin or ankle (you can use a block). Perform this movement through extension: both the right and left sides are lengthened, the back remains straight.\nExtend the left arm upwards, with the shoulders in line.\nConcentrate your gaze on the fingertips of the left hand.\nBreathe deeply and feel even stretching.\n</string>
    <string name="asana_3_exit">gently reach for the left palm through the diagonal sideways, return the body to a straight position. Repeat on the other leg</string>
    <string name="asana_4">Prasarita Padottanasana\na pose with legs wide apart and stretched out\n</string>
    <string name="asana_4_title">Start with Tadasana.\nSpread the feet so that they are at the width of the arms stretched out to the side.\nThe outer parts of the feet should be parallel to the shortcut of the mat, and the toes should be slightly turned inwards.\nAs you exhale, lean forward, keeping the pelvis in the original position: do not shift it backwards relative to the heels.\nPlace your hands on the floor or blocks. You can place your palms at the level of the feet or slightly in front of them. Alternatively, fold the palms of your hands into the elbow bends, gently guiding the top of your head to the floor. To deepen the incline, you can grasp the big toes and point the elbows out to the sides.\nWith the weight distributed on the feet, actively load the toes. This will help to align the pelvis and prevent backward deviation.\nThe neck is relaxed, do not clamp it with the shoulders.\n</string>
    <string name="asana_4_exit">on exhalation gently rise. If you feel dizzy, you can stay in an intermediate position: put your palms on the floor, under your shoulders, and breathe a little.</string>
    <string name="asana_5">Dandasana \npose stick\n</string>
    <string name="asana_5_title">Sit on the floor and stretch your legs out in front of you. Bring the feet together and point the toes towards you. Use your hands to pull the buttocks back to feel the sciatic bones and push away from them.\nLower your hands so that your fingertips are on either side of your pelvis, palms pressed firmly to the floor.\nTurn your hips slightly inwards, leveling the position of your legs.\nPull the spine upwards: imagine it lengthening between the tailbone and the head.\nStay for at least 1 minute, breathing deeply and evenly.\n</string>
    <string name="asana_6">Vajrasana\ndiamond pose</string>
    <string name="asana_6_title">Kneel on your knees with your feet together.\nSlowly lower the buttocks to the heels.\nThe palms of your hands are open to the ceiling and relaxed on your thighs.\nKeep your back straight, do not fall backwards.\nConcentrate on breathing and carefully monitor the sensations in the body. If there are areas of tension, direct relaxing exhalation there.\nYou can stay in the pose for up to five minutes. It is important that no discomfort accumulates and that you feel comfortable.\n\n</string>
    <string name="asana_7">Virasana - hero\'s pose</string>
    <string name="asana_7_title">From a kneeling position, spread your legs about hip-width apart.\nSlowly lower the pelvis downwards, using your hands to pull the shins slightly apart. If this variant of the exercise is very uncomfortable, place blocks under the pelvis.\nThe soles of the feet face upwards, toes backwards, Pull the knees together if possible.\nStretch behind the top of the head upwards, avoiding a bend in the lower back. Tighten the abdomen to relieve tension in the back muscles.\nPlace your hands in front of your chest in namaste, or place the back of your hands on your thighs\n</string>
    <string name="asana_7_exit">rest your palms on the mat, lift your pelvis, bring your shins and feet together. Return to Vajrasana</string>
    <string name="asana_8">Bakasana crane pose</string>
    <string name="asana_8_title">From Malasana, stretch your arms forward and place them on the floor. Fingers spread wide apart for maximum grip on the mat.\nContinuing to press the hips against the body, lift up on the toes, resting the knees on the shoulders.\nPulling away from the arms, spread the shoulder blades apart, shoulders pointing backwards. Create resistance: simultaneously press the knees into the shoulders and the shoulders into the knees.\nCarefully shift your body weight onto your hands and try to lift your feet off the floor one by one, pushing your body weight forward.\nIf the previous work was easy for you, you can move to full balance - lift both legs, directing the pelvis to the heels. The photo shows the lower variant of Bakasana, and if you have already mastered it, you can switch to the upper one. To do this, gradually straighten your arms at the elbows without losing the position of your legs and body.\nIf these variants are not available yet, you can perform the so-called baby Bakasana. In this case, rest your forearms on the floor, pointing the fingers of your hands forward. The area of support increases and it is easier to get into balance\n</string>
    <string name="asana_9">Shavasana  corpse pose</string>
    <string name="asana_9_title">At the end of the complex, sit in Dandasana and start slowly lowering the body downwards, feeling the vertebrae touch the floor one by one. Perform this movement slowly, rounding the back.\nWhen the body is on the floor, spread the arms slightly apart, opening the armpits.\nCover your eyes. Take a deep breath in through the nose and exhale through the mouth - voicing. When the residual tension passes, we move to free breathing and immerse ourselves in the observation of internal processes.\n\nYou can stay in Shavasana for five to thirty minutes. Depending on the intensity of the practice that preceded it. If you have been practising for a short time and do not feel very tired, you can shorten the time in asana. The main thing is to have time to calm down, study the sensations in the body and fully recover.\n</string>
    <string name="asana_10">Halasana plough pose</string>
    <string name="asana_10_title">From lying on your back, put your hands behind your head. Straight or bent legs point towards the palms. Roll over smoothly, not jerkily.\nThe weight of the body is on the shoulders and shoulder blades - the head and neck are not involved.\nToes can be placed in the palms or near them. If possible, straighten the legs at the knees.\nRoll on the shoulder blades to feel how the spine lengthens and stretches - the back relaxes.\n</string>
    <string name="asana_10_exit">gently and as slowly as possible, roll back onto the mat. Help with your hands, legs can be bent at the knees.</string>
    <string name="asana_11">Karna Pidasana</string>
    <string name="asana_11_title">Build up Halasana and then bring the bent legs towards the head and place them with the knees on the sides of the ears.\nKeeping the pelvis vertical over the shoulders, pull the shins and ankles towards the floor. If you can do this, place your feet on the insteps. If not, leave them on the toes.\nPlace your hands on your ankles or stretch along the mat behind your back.\nLightly clasp the shoulders over the ears.\n</string>
    <string name="asana_11_in">breathe evenly, trying not to clamp the chest and relieve the neck. Relax the jaw.\n</string>
    <string name="asana_11_exit">return to Halasana and slowly, vertebra by vertebra, lower the back, then the legs.</string>
    <string name="asana_12">Salamba Sarvangasana\n</string>
    <string name="asana_12_title">Let\'s consider the exit from Halasana.\nFrom Halasana put your hands behind your back and pick up the body - thumbs pointing away from the spine, the rest upwards.\nStart lifting the legs to the vertical position - one or both at a time.\nDirect the elbows towards each other - they should not move apart.\nTurn your hips inwards, pull your legs up by your toes. In the final version, the body and legs are lined up in one line.\nPress the palms of the hands on the back to push the chest to the chin. The main weight is on the shoulders.\n</string>
    <string name="asana_12_exit">bring the legs behind the head and then return to lying on the back - no jerking or sudden movements.</string>
    <string name="asana_13">Sukhasana and Parivritta Sukhasana\n</string>
    <string name="asana_13_title">Sit with crossed legs - take the heels a little further away from the pelvis, so that you get a triangle, if you look from above. Heels under the knees. Check that the pelvis is straight and both sciatic bones are pressed against the mat or floor. Push off from this support and reach for the top of the head upwards. In order not to have a bend in the lower back, pull the belly up slightly, pointing the navel towards the spine.\nBring the shoulders back in a circular motion and lower them down. The chin is also slightly lowered down to stretch and relax the back of the neck. Take 5-10 deep inhalations and exhalations here, filling the abdomen and ribs with air. With the next exhalation, turn to the right - place the right hand behind the back, but do not transfer the body weight to it. With the left palm hug the knee or thigh of the right leg. Keep your back straight and continue to stretch your head towards the ceiling. Stay here for 3-5 cycles of deep breathing. On exhalation return to the centre and perform the exercise on the other side.\nSimplifications. A rolled up blanket or blocks can be placed under the pelvic bones. If during twisting the breathing becomes shallow and there is a feeling of tightness in the abdominal or thoracic region, you should turn forward slightly and release the tension.\nBenefits. Static position helps to concentrate, to realise the sensations in the body, to immerse oneself in watching the breath, to calm the mind, to form the posture. In twisting there is a stimulation of the abdominal organs, increases the mobility of the vertebrae.\n</string>
    <string name="asana_14">Marjariasana\n</string>
    <string name="asana_14_title">Technique. Stand on four points of support - palms of hands and elevations of feet. Make sure that the shoulders are above the wrists, the hands are shoulder-width apart and the pelvic bones are above the knees. Slightly tuck the lower ribs and navel inward, which smooths out the lumbar flexion and helps you get into a straight back position. Imagine the whole body coming together in the centre - it is strong and immovable. Linger in this position for a few breath cycles. Now we move to the dynamics: on the inhalation we perform a bend, directing the top of the head and tailbone to the ceiling, with the exhalation we round the upper back and push the shoulder blades apart from the spine. Perform this movement 7-10 times - gently, feeling how the spine is being developed.\nSimplifications. If the wrists are weak, perform the form on the forearms.\nBenefits. Relieves back pain and increases mobility of the spine - it improves blood supply to the intervertebral discs. Relieves unpleasant symptoms during critical days\n</string>
    <string name="asana_15">Ardha Bhujangasana\n</string>
    <string name="asana_15_title">Technique. From the position lying on the stomach place the palms of your hands a little further away from the head. With an inhalation lift the head and the thoracic region upwards, avoiding pain in the lower back. Rest your forearms on the floor and pull the mat towards you. Tighten your shoulder blades to your spine and pull the top of your head towards the mat - do not tilt your head back. Glutes and hips tucked in, feet at pelvic width or closer.\nSimplifications. If there is discomfort in the lower back, put your hands further away from the body. Benefits. Opens the thoracic region, increases the mobility of the vertebrae, eliminates the feeling of stiffness in the spine, improves the digestive system\n</string>
    <string name="asana_16">Malasana\n</string>
    <string name="asana_16_title">﻿In Tadasana we spread our legs about the width of the mat and lower the pelvis downwards. Toes can look forward or to the sides. Join palms in front of the chest in namaste and push the thighs apart with the elbows, at the same time pulling the thighs to the body - resistance work. Pull the pelvis downwards and the top of the head upwards - stretch the spine. Linger in Malasana for 8-10 cycles of breathing.\nSimplifications. If you cannot put your heels on the floor, you can put a rolled-up plaid under them. Benefits. Develops hip joints, improves blood circulation in the pelvic organs, relieves painful sensations during menstruation.\n</string>
    <string name="asana_17">Balasana</string>
    <string name="asana_17_title">Technique of performance. Sit on your heels and then lower your belly on your thighs, head on the floor. Put your hands back and place them along the body. Maximally relax the back muscles and with each exhalation release all the tension. Linger in the child\'s pose for 10 deep cycles of breathing.\nSimplifications. If the head does not fall to the floor, you can put a block or pillow under the forehead, put one fist on the other for support.\nBenefits. Relaxes the muscles of the back, relieves painful sensations in the lumbar region, turns on the parasympathetic part of the nervous system.\n</string>
    <string name="in_asana">"In asana: "</string>
    <string name="exit">"exit: "</string>
    <string name="sound">sound\n</string>
    <string name="missed_us">Missed us?</string>
    <string name="push_title">Long time no see in our app. Please, log in and see what\'s new!</string>
</resources>